punditarena.com 2019-06-20

# Privacy Policy - Pundit Arena

**PUNDIT ARENA:**

**PRIVACY POLICY – LAST UPDATED 06 August 2014**

**1.          GENERAL:**

1.1       This Privacy Policy (the “Policy”) is a legal agreement between you (the “End User” or “you”) and Readia Ltd, a limited Company, whose operational place of business is Pundit Arena HQ, 74 South Mall, Cork, Ireland (the “Company”, “PA”, “we”).

1.2       Pundit Arena knows that you care about how your personal information is used and shared, and we take your privacy seriously. We are committed to protecting the privacy of our End Users and we strive to provide a safe and secure End User experience. Please read below to learn more about our privacy policy.

1.3       This Policy forms part of the Terms of Use Agreement which binds all users of this site and is available by [clicking here](https://www.punditarena.com/terms/ "Terms of Use"). We suggest that you review it before you begin to use Pundit Arena.

**2:          POLICY SCOPE:                        ****What does this Privacy Policy cover?**

2.1       This Policy sets out the types of information we collect and hold about you and which you submit to us by means of the Website and the Application, the purposes for which such information is collected, the uses made of such information, details of any persons to whom we disclose such information and other steps we take to protect your privacy.

2.2       Please be advised that all personal identifiable information (“ **Relevant** **Personal** **Data** ”) that you may confidentially provide to us relating to you, save such information you submit in contravention of this Policy, such as but not limited to posting personal information via public comments, will be treated in accordance with the provisions of the Data Protection Acts, 1988 to 2003 and any replacement or amending legislation.

2.3       PA also collects certain types of non-personally identifiable information “ **Information** ” whenever a user interacts with Pundit Arena.

2.4       You explicitly accept, without limitation or qualification, to the collection, use and transfer of the Relevant Personal Data provided by you in the manner described in this Policy. **IF FOR ANY REASON YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THE PROVISIONS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY, THEN YOU SHOULD NOT USE THE SOLUTION OR, IF YOU HAVE ALREADY USED THE SOLUTION, THEN YOU SHOULD CEASE SUCH USE OR ACCESS WITH IMMEDIATE EFFECT**.

**3.          USER INFORMATION:   What information about Users does Pundit Arena collect?**

**3.1        Automatic Information**

**3.1.1.**   **General:** Our primary goal in collecting Relevant Personal Data and Information is to provide Users with the best and most useful content to help improve your experience with Pundit Arena. In addition to any information you choose to submit to us, we or selected third parties, may use a variety of technologies that store or access information already stored on a personal computer, laptop, tablet and/or mobile phone (each a “ **Device** ”) interacting with Pundit Arena. ** **

**3.1.2    **We collect certain kinds of information about our users for the following reasons:

**a)          **To provide personalized services unique to individual users;

**b)          **To help us monitor and improve the services we offer;

**c)          **To verify your identity as a registered End User and of a particular End User Account; and

**d)          **To monitor use of Pundit Arena to ensure the highest levels of security and safety are maintained.

**3.1.3.   Technologies we use: **A few of the methods that may be used to store or access information already stored on your Device include the following (and in future other technology and methods will be developed):

_**Cookies**_ – a cookie is a text file placed on a device when a user visits a website. Cookies can be read by the website on your subsequent visits. The information stored in a cookie may relate to your browsing habits on the web page, or a unique identification number so that the website can ‘remember’ you on your return visit. Cookies can be temporary (e.g. session) or permanent (e.g. persistent). They can also be first party (e.g. placed by us) or third party (e.g. placed by a third party application).

The following is a listing of the main cookies used on our site together with brief details of the information they store and for what purpose;

i)               **Site performance cookies** _:_ This type of cookie remembers your preferences/settings for tools found on the Solution.

ii)             **Analytics cookies _:_** Every time a user visits Pundit Arena, web analytics software provided by a third party generates an anonymous analytics cookie. These cookies can tell us whether or not you have visited the site before. Your browser will tell us if you have these cookies, and if you don’t, we generate new ones. This allows us to track how many individual unique users we have, and how often they visit the site. Unless you are signed in to the Solution, these cookies cannot be used to identify individuals; they are used for statistical purposes only. If you are logged in, we will also know the details you gave to us for this, such as email address and password.

iii)            **_Registration cookies:_** When you register with Pundit Arena, we generate cookies that signal whether you are signed in or not. Our servers use these cookies to work out which type of account you are signed in with, and if you are allowed access to a particular service. It also allows us to associate any comments you post with your Account. We combine information from your registration cookies with analytics cookies, which we could use to identify which pages you have seen on Pundit Arena.

iv)            **_Third party cookies:_** these are cookies found in other companies’ internet tools which we are using to enhance our site, for example:

_Flash cookies_ —a Flash cookie (or locally shared object) is a data file placed on your device via the Adobe Flash plug-in that may be built-in to or downloaded by you to your device. This can operate across all your browsers.

HTML5—HTML5 cookies can be programmed through HTML5 local storage and do not require a plug-in

_ETag or entity tag_ —an opaque identifier assigned by a web server to a specific version of a resource found at a URL that acts as a form of device identifier.

_Google Analytics –_ _to provide statistics these use visitors’ IP addresses but do not have access to users’ usernames or email addresses. You can find further information on the information which it collects at_<http://www.google.com/analytics/> _._

Please note, the companies that generate these cookies have their own privacy policies PA has no access to read or write these cookies, other than allowing them to be served, we have no role to play in these cookies at all (although we may use statistical information arising from these third party cookies and provided to us by third parties, to improve the targeting of content to End Users). These third party cookies may be used by those third parties to anonymously target to you on other websites, based on your visit to Pundit Arena.

**3.1.4    Choice: **We receive and may store any information you enter on our website or provide to us in any other way (including by connecting to Pundit Arena through a third-party service). You can choose not to provide us with certain information, but then you may not be able to take advantage of many of our special features. The personal information we collect includes:

a)         **Registration:** In order for you to use certain Pundit Arena services, such as submitting new articles to the website, you must complete a registration form including your full name and email address, or connect with us through a third-party service, which will provide us with information about you from your account with that service as that service may permit.

b)         **Member Profile** : You have the option (but are not required) to enter your full name and the URL of your blog into your member profile for public display on Pundit Arena.

c)         **User Generated Content** :  This is the provision of comments via the comments panel.

The “ **help** ” portion of the toolbar on the majority of browsers will direct you on how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to command the browser to tell you when you receive a new cookie, or how to fully disable cookies. You may choose to disable or reject cookies when using Pundit Arena, but you may not be able to access some of Pundit Arena’s more attractive features.

You have the right object to the use of information collection technologies. Regular cookies may generally be disabled or removed by tools that are available as part of most commercial browsers; and in some but not all instances, can be blocked in the future by selecting certain settings. Each browser you use will need to be set separately and different browsers offer different functionality and options in this regard. Also, these tools may not be effective with regard to Flash cookies or HTML5 cookies. For information on disabling Flash cookies go to Adobe’s website ([www.adobe.com](http://www.adobe.com/)).

**3.2.      Your consent and your right to refuse the use of information collection technologies:**

3.2.1    Pundit Arena does not collect personally identifiable information from users who are not registered and logged into the website. If you are logged into a third party social network and you comment on an article, your profile on any such social network will identify you as that user, but your personal information will not be available to Pundit Arena.

3.2.2    On registration, we obtain your consent to our information collection technologies through our opt-in mechanism and by providing you with transparent information in this Policy and providing you with the opportunity to make your choice as to whether or not you consent to these terms. If you do not consent, you will not have registered access to Pundit Arena.

3.3       **What we use the information for:**

**3.3.1    Non Personal/ Non-Identifiable Information:**

As detailed above, we collect a certain amount of statistical, behavioural and non-personal information in relation to your use of Pundit Arena, including the content accessed, the services you access, referring website addresses, the number of visitors to the website or the Application and this information is used to improve Pundit Arena’s functionality by making it easier to navigate, troubleshooting problems and by allowing for us to provide relevant information on individual sections of the website and/or Application.

**3.3.2    Relevant Personal Data:**

In addition to collecting such statistical and non-personal information, we also collect Relevant Personal Data from you when you register with Pundit Arena. This may include among other items, such information as your name, email address, home address, telephone number, and any other information we reasonably require to verify you as the End User Account holder. This information will only be kept by Pundit Arena for the duration of the existence of the registered account, plus a reasonable time, to facilitate back up and subsequent access by you at a later time.

**3.4        How information Is used:**

3.4.1    We use the information submitted to and gathered, to support the website and the application, we aggregate data, provide reports, respond to any queries you may have, operate and improve the website and the application, and strive to foster a positive End User experience and delivery of Pundit Arena.

**3.5        Registration:**

3.5.1    By registering with Pundit Arena, by managing your account, by using the website and the services or opting in when presented with choices, you have consented to Pundit Arena’s use of your information, subject to local law, in the following ways:

  * to allow you to create an account;
  * to create a profile for you based on information that you have provided to us;
  * to contact you about Pundit Arena updates, informational and service-related communications, including important security updates;
  * to enable you to provide feedback, to contact us and for us to respond to you;
  * to conduct surveys, questionnaires, promotions and contests;
  * to generate internal reports and information;
  * to allow you to submit articles;
  * to allow you to engage in any reward schemes we may have in place for contributors;

3.5.2    The only people that will contact you as a consequence of use of the Pundit Arena are PA employees or representatives. All such contact will be performed in a secure manner through your account.

**3.6        Public Information:** Please note, if you post personal information in an area of the Website or the Application which is a public area or is capable of being accessed, used and stored by others around the world, including those in countries that might not have legislation adequately guaranteeing the protection of your personal information, you agree to hold Pundit Arena harmless in respect of such action and any and all direct, indirect and consequential losses arising therefrom.

While Pundit Arena takes measures to safeguard your information from unauthorised access, Pundit Arena does not accept responsibility for the use of information posted or otherwise made available in a public area, whether open to other users where it would not normally have been or open to the public domain around the world. Please ensure that you do not post sensitive information, including personal information to any public area of the Website or the Application. A breach of this condition shall be considered to be a material breach of the terms of the Terms of Use and this Policy and is terminable at the discretion of the Company.

Please note that ideas you post and information you share may be seen and used by other users, and Pundit Arena cannot guarantee that other users will not use the ideas and information that you share on Pundit Arena. Therefore, if you have an idea or information that you would like to keep confidential and/or don’t want others to use, or that is subject to third party rights that may be infringed by your sharing it, do not share it on Pundit Arena. PUNDIT ARENA IS NOT RESPONSIBLE FOR AN END USER’S MISUSE OR MISAPPROPRIATION OF ANY CONTENT OR INFORMATION POSTED, UPLOADED, OR TRANSMITTED WITHIN THE WEBSITE OR THE APPLICATION.

4.         **DISCLOSURE OF INFORMATION TO OTHERS**

4.1       We disclose your information to third parties. This could be personal, behavioural, indirect or non-personal information. The rules governing such disclosure are set out below.

4.2       We may share your information with third parties who help us in the delivery of our own Services. We disclose information to companies and individuals we employ or use to perform functions on our behalf including support companies. Examples include hosting our web servers, analysing data, providing marketing assistance, and providing customer service. These companies and individuals will have access to your personal information as may be necessary to perform their functions, but they may not share that information with any other third party or use that data for any other purpose. We will remain the data controller of your Relevant Personal Data and be responsible for any information shared in this way.

4.3       We also share aggregated anonymous information about visitors with clients, partners, investors and advisors, so that they can understand the kinds of visitors to Pundit Arena and how those visitors use it. Such aggregated data does not identify users individually.

4.4       We disclose information if legally required to do so, or at our discretion pursuant to a request from a governmental entity or if we believe in good faith – after considering your privacy interests and other factors – that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to legal requirements or comply with legal process; (b) protect our rights or property or our affiliated companies; (c) prevent a crime; or (d) protect the personal safety of users or the public.

4.5       We may disclose and transfer such information to a third party who acquires any or all of Pundit Arena’s business units, whether such acquisition is by way of merger, consolidation or purchase of all or a substantial portion of our assets. In addition, in the event PA becomes the subject of an insolvency proceeding, whether voluntary or involuntary, PA or its liquidator, administrator or receiver may sell, license or otherwise dispose of such information in a transaction approved by the court. You will be notified of the sale of all or a substantial portion of our business to a third party by email or through a prominent notice posted on the Website.

4.6       Please note that certain information, statements, data, and content (such as photographs and videos) which you may submit to Pundit Arena via comments are likely to, reveal your gender, ethnic origin, nationality, age, and/or other personal information about you. You acknowledge that your submission of any information, statements, data, and content to us is voluntary on your part.

4.7       Please note that you control the flow of information to and from your Pundit Arena account, as well as any third party social media accounts and it is based on the privacy settings in these accounts which dictate what people can and cannot see or do. You should review your permission settings on a regular basis so that you are fully aware of the information being provided to other End Users.

**5           ACCESS, RECTIFICATION AND REMOVAL**

5.1       If you choose to register with Pundit Arena, you may have access to, review, correct, update, change or delete your account profile information at any time. This is completed by simply logging into your account and making the necessary changes. Such access must be completed through the verification or authentication log in process. Access may be denied if you fail to enter the correct information.

5.2       Pundit Arena retains all the information gathered about you in an effort to make your repeat use with us more efficient, practical and relevant until you change or remove your personal data as described herein. Under law, you have a right to access the personal information that we hold about you, for which we may charge a fee. If you wish to access such information, please send an email to [    insert url   ].

5.3.      We will respond to information access requests within 30 days of receipt. If we require additional time to provide access to your information, we will acknowledge receipt of your request within 30 days and promptly supplement our response within the time period required by applicable law.

5.4       If your account is terminated for any reason in accordance with the Terms of Use Agreement and/or you do not log into your account for a significant period of time, it will expire and be scheduled for deletion. Our current expiration and deletion period is 36 months; we may extend or reduce this period in order to adjust to changing patterns. If we change the period, we will update this notice. You will always receive an email from us before we delete your account, and you always have the ability to delete your account at any time by logging into your account. Deletion of expired accounts occurs on a periodic basis and includes the deletion of all applicable account data including contact information.

5.5       If you do not want your information to be processed as described by this Policy, you may revoke your consent to our Policy. If you wish to do so, please contact us at: [    insert url   ]. However, please note that if you do withdraw your consent, you will not be able to use the full and attractive services offered by Pundit Arena and your account and profile information will be deleted.

**6           CONTACT**

6.1       Unless you have indicated otherwise by ticking the “opt out” box when registering with us, we can use your personal information to provide you with details of our services, products and promotions, including contacting you by email. If at any time you no longer wish to receive such emails, you can unsubscribe by clicking on the applicable link contained in the information email sent to you. You can also adjust your registration details and opt out of receiving such emails and other communications by ticking the appropriate “opt out” box or configuring this setting in your account settings.

**7          CHANGES**

**7.1        **If we decide to materially change the substance of this Policy, we will, where required, contact you via the email address that you maintain in your account. We will also post those changes through a prominent notice on the Solution so that you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information, and to whom we will disclose it.
